A Guide to the Department of Confederate Military Records, 1859-1996
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Department of Confederate Military Records, 1859-1996
Library of Virginia
27684
68.19 cubic feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Adjutant General's Office, Dept. of Military Affairs, 506 Ninth St. Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, 4 April 1918.
Agency History
Interest in memorializing Confederate veterans prompted the General Assembly to pass an act on March 13, 1884, directing the adjutant general to compile a roster of all those who served from Virginia in the Confederate armed forces. The Adjutant General distributed blank roster sheets to former company commanders and other individuals, however, most of the sheets were never returned and the project was left unfinished. On January 25, 1898, another act was passed and later re-enacted on March 6, 1900, to provide a roster of all the ex-Confederate soldiers living in the State of Virginia. The commissioners of revenue throughout the Commonwealth were furnished with blank roster sheets from the auditor of public accounts to record the name, age, rank, company, regiment, date of enlistment, and length of service of all former Confederate soldiers living in the state of Virginia. The result of this endeavor was a two-volume roster of ex-Confederate soldiers and sailors arranged by locality. A more comprehensive inventory of Virginia soldiers, dead or alive, who fought for the Confederacy was still in want. In response to Congress' passage of an act on February 25, 1903, providing for the assembling of muster rolls for all Union and Confederate soldiers, Virginia created the Office of the Secretary of Virginia Military Records on March 7, 1904, to assist the Secretary of War and the U.S. War Department with a complete roster of Confederate soldiers from Virginia.
Major Robert Waterman Hunter, a former soldier in the 179th Regiment Virginia Militia and officer in the 2nd Regiment Virginia Volunteers, was appointed for one year by Governor Andrew Jackson Montague upon the recommendation of the Grand Commander of the Grand Camp of Confederate Veterans, as the first Secretary of Virginia Military Records. His duties were to "collect all muster rolls, records, and other materials showing the officers and enlisted men of the several companies, battalions, regiments, and other military organizations from Virginia in the armies, marine or naval service of the Confederate States." These records were to be obtained by the secretary through gift or loan and deposited in the Virginia State Library. The General Assembly passed legislation on February 20, 1906, and again on March 9, 1908, reappointing the Secretary of Virginia Military Records, further expanding the duties of the office, and providing a salary for the position. Hunter submitted a report to Governor Claude A. Swanson in 1909 detailing the accomplishments of the office. Hunter noted in this report the completion of various lists of officers, surgeons, chaplains, battles in Virginia and West Virginia, and the collection of rolls and rosters, both original and secondary, of Virginia companies calendared in books of the office according to branch, regiment or battalion, and company.
Colonel Joseph Virginius Bidgood, former Commander of the Grand Camp of Confederate Veterans, succeeded Hunter in 1910 as Secretary of Virginia Military Records. The Office of the Secretary of Virginia Military Records merged into the Adjutant General's office on February 28, 1911. The Department of Confederate Military Records was formed by an act of the General Assembly on March 12, 1912. This act replaced the Office of the Secretary of Virginia Military Records and appointed the secretary for a term of two years to be paid out of the Military Fund. The Department of Confederate Military Records, under the Office of the Adjutant General, continued the work of the Secretary of Virginia Military Records of assembling muster rolls and other documents related to Virginians in the Civil War. In 1918, the General Assembly passed an act abolishing the Department of Confederate Military Records and transferring the department's records to the Virginia State Library.
Scope and Content Information
Records, 1859-1996 (bulk 1861-1864, 1905-1918), of the Dept. of Confederate Military Records. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1861 to 1864, 1884, 1900, and 1905 to 1918. Includes correspondence, muster rolls, payrolls, clippings, descriptive rolls of pay and clothing, powers of attorney, rosters, printed material, scrapbooks, letter books, general and special orders, certificates, photographs, and other sundry items.
Organization
Organized into the following four series: I. Correspondence; II. Unit Records; III. Miscellaneous Records; IV. Confederate Rosters.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence
  Contains both incoming and outgoing correspondence to/from Major Robert W. Hunter or Colonel Joseph V. Bidgood, both Secretaries of Virginia Military Records. The majority of the correspondence, however, was addressed to Col. Bidgood since he took over the duties in 1910. The correspondence primarily relates to service records of Virginians during the Civil War. Individuals wrote Bidgood for information about soldiers for pensions, genealogical & historical research, and other purposes. There is often a typescript copy of Bidgood's reply attached to the incoming correspondence. Bidgood wrote to veterans, veterans' families, clerks of the county courts, and others seeking information about soldiers and requesting copies of muster rolls. These records are particularly useful because they often contain the personal recollections of veterans and their families. As a result, genealogical information can sometimes be gleaned from the correspondence.
  Special correspondence is arranged at the rear of this series. Included are letters from Joseph Reid Anderson, Jr., son of the former owner of the Tredegar Iron Works; General Thomas T. Munford, Grand Commander Grand Camp Confederate Veterans; Generals Francis C. Ainsworth & Robert Shaw Oliver, Secretaries of the War Department; Governors Claude A. Swanson, A.J. Montague, and William Hodges Mann; John Hart, editor of "Our Confederate Column" in the Richmond Times-Dispatch; and Adjutant Generals James McDonald & W.W. Sale. Joseph Reid Anderson corresponded frequently with Bidgood while serving as the compiler and editor of the "VMI Biography." Munford wrote to Major Robert W. Hunter and later Colonel Bidgood requesting names of soldiers, discussing the restoration of the flag & seal of Virginia, and addressing a controversy regarding his commission as general succeeding General Wickham. Ainsworth wrote about transferring records from the War Department to the Secretary of Virginia Military Records to assist in the project of compiling a complete roll of Confederate soldiers from Virginia. The correspondence from the various governors is mostly letters sent directly to the governor's office which is being transferred to the Secretary of Virginia Military Records. The governors simply ask Bidgood if they can respond for them to various inquiries about Civil War soldiers from Virginia citizens.
  - A
    - Abbott-Amiss, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ancell-Arnell, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ashby-Ayres, 1910-1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - B
    - Bagby-Baylor, 1910-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Beach-Bevill, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bierbower-Blumenthal, 1910-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Boggs-Boylestown, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bragg-Bryant, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Buchanan-Byrd, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - C
    - Caine-Caulfield, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cecil-Cloyd, 1910-1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Coates-Cox, 1910-1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Craddock-Cutler, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - D
    - Dalton-Denny, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dickerson-Douthat, 1910-1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Drewry-Dwyer, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - E, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - F
    - Farinholt-Fowler, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Franklin-Fuller, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - G
    - Gabriel-Glass, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Goad-Green, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Gregory-Gwaltney, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - H
    - Haas-Harrington, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Harris-Hazelwood, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Healey-Hoen, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Hogan-Hurst, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hurt-Hyde, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Hurtley, Mora Kingsley, 1911-1914 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I, 1912-1916 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - J
    - Jacks-Jewett, 1910-1916 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Johnson-Judson, 1910-1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - K, 1910-1916 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - L
    - Lamb-Lewis, 1910-1916 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Lida-Lyon, 1910-1917 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - M
    - Mabry-Martin, 1910-1917 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Martz-Mayo, 1910-1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - McAnelly-McNeil, 1910-1917 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Meade-Mithell, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Moffett-Moorefield, 1910-1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Morgan-Myers, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - N, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - O, 1910-1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - P
    - Page-Payne, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Peak-Power, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Pratt-Pyle, 1910-1917 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Q, 1911-1916 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - R
    - Rainey-Reynolds, 1910-1916 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Rice-Ryan, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - S
    - Safford-Sewell, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Shannon-Sloan, 1910-1917 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Smith-Smithers, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Snead-Stoves, 1910-1917 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Stratton-Synge, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - T
    - Talcott-Terrell, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Thieman-Turner, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Tyler-Tynes, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - U, 1910-1916 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - V, 1911-1916 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - W
    - Wade-Watts, 1910-1917 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Weaver-Whitman, 1910-1917 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Wiatt-Wise, 1910-1917 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Witcher, A. A., 1910-1911 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Wood-Wythe, 1910-1917 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Y-Z, 1910-1913 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, 1910-1913 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Special Correspondence
    - Ainsworth, Frank C. (Sec. of War), 1905-1913 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Joseph Reid, Jr., 1910-1917 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Adjutant Generals
      - McDonald, James, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Sale, William Wilson, 1911-1913 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Sale, William Wilson, 1914-1917 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Governors
      - Lee, Fitzhugh, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Mann, William Hodges, 1910-1914 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Montague, A.J., 1903-1916 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Stuart, Henry C., 1914-1916 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Swanson, Claude A., 1910-1913 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hart, John (Editor, Confederate Column), 1910-1914 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Hunter, Robert M. (former Sec. of Confederate Military Records), 1905-1908 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Hunter, Robert M. (former Sec. of Confederate Military Records), 1909, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Munford, Thomas P., 1904-1914 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - State Librarians
      - McIlwaine, H. R., 1912-1919 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Robinson, Morgan P., 1921 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Series II: Unit Records
  Contains rosters, muster rolls, payrolls, powers of attorney, special orders, descriptive lists of pay & clothing, notes, correspondence, regimental histories, pamphlets, certificates issued by the War Department, roll books, field returns, monthly reports, clippings, and other sundry items. These materials document Confederate veterans from Virginia who served in artillery, cavalry, infantry, local defense, reserves, Virginia state line, militia, and various other units during the Civil War. There are both original materials from the Civil War and secondary materials gathered by the Secretaries of Virginia Military Records or the Adjutant General. For example, there are both original muster rolls and rosters compiled as per the Acts of the General Assembly in 1884 and 1900. There are often hand-written notes and rough drafts of rosters by Hunter or Bidgood with each unit's file. The rough drafts of rosters simply duplicate the information contained in the Confederate rosters compiled by the department. Whenever possible, the name on the unit file corresponds with the name cited in Wallace's "A Guide to Virginia Military Organizations." Note that some materials have been added to the collection since it was deposited at the State Library in 1918.
  - Subseries 1: Artillery
    - Regiments
      - 1st
        - Co. A (Washington Artillery), 1884-1911 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Co. C (2nd) (Henrico Artillery), 1908 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Co. F (Williamsburg Artillery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Co. G (Peninsula Artillery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous (See Oversized - Box 1), 1862-1863 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 1st (Pendleton's) Light Artillery
        - Co. C (Newton Artillery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 2nd
        - Co. A (Burfoot's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Co. B (Charlotte & Lunenburg Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Co. C (Southside Artillery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Co. D (Alexander's Co.) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Co. E (McGehee's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Co. F (Lunenburg Rebel Artillery), 1862-1911 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Co. G (Johnson's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Co. H (Cosby's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - Co. I (Farrar's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Co. K (Hanes' Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 1), 1862 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 4th
        - Co. B (Mecklenburg Heavy Arty), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Co. C (Davis Artillery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - Co. D (Green Rough & Readys), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - Co. F (Edmondson's Battery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 20)
        - Co. I (Sales' Battery), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Battalions
      - 10th
        - Co. A (Metropolitan Guards), 1913 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Co. B (Hensley's Battery) (See Oversized - Box 1), 1862-1915 (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Co. C (Allen Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1861-1863 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Co. D (Brandon/Jamestown Heavy Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1862-1910 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Co. E (Blake's Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 12th
        - Co. A (1st) (Brooke's Battery) (See Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Co. A (2nd) (Sturdivant's Battery), 1896-1909 (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - Co. B (Martin's Battery), 1912 (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - Co. C (Eubank's Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 9)
        - Co. D (Harrington Light Artillery), 1890 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - 13th
        - Co. A (Otey Battery), 1911 (Box 10, Folder 11)
        - Co. B (Ringgold Battery), 1909-1912 (Box 10, Folder 12)
        - Co. C (Davidson's Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - 18th
        - Field & Staff Officers, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - Co. A (Southampton Lee Artillery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
        - Co. B (Atlantic Artillery), 1916 (Box 10, Folder 16)
        - Co. C (Cockade Mounted Battery), 1911 (Box 10, Folder 17)
        - Co. D (Peyton Artillery), 1884-1914 (Box 10, Folder 18)
        - Co. E (Alexandria Artillery) (See Oversized - Box 1), 1900 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - 19th
        - Field & Staff Officers, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 20)
        - Co. A (Old Dominion Light Arty) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1886 (Box 10, Folder 21)
        - Co. B (Bossieux Guards), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - Co. C (United Artillery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 23)
        - Co. C (3rd) (Irish Volunteers), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 24)
        - Co. D (Campbell's Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 25)
        - Co. E (3rd) (Savage's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - 20th
        - Co. B (St. Bride's Artillery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 27)
        - Co. C (Jones' Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
        - Co. C (Williams' Battery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1864 (Box 10, Folder 29)
        - Co. D (Hargrove's Battery), 1905-1914 (Box 10, Folder 30)
        - Co. E (Dabney's Battery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - 38th
        - Co. A (Fauquier Artillery), 1904 (Box 10, Folder 32)
        - Co. B (Richmond Fayette Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1861-1905 (Box 10, Folder 33)
        - Co. C (Hampden Artillery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 34)
        - Co. C (Thomas Artillery), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 35)
        - Co. D (Latham's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1912 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Independent Batteries
      - Allen's Co. Va. Heavy Arty. (Lunenburg Rebel Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1863-1911 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Armistead's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Mathews Light Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1862 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Barr's Co. Va. Light Arty. (formerly Lewis' Co.), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Brown's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Wise Arty), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Bryan's Co. Va. Arty. (Monroe Artillery), 1904 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Carpenter's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Alleghany Artillery), 1893-1905 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Carrington's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Charlottesville Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1863 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Carter's (J.W.) Co. Va. Horse Arty. (formerly Chew's Co.), 1907-1909 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Carter's (W.P.P.) Co. Va. Light Arty. (King William Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Cayce's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Purcell Arty.), 1911-1915 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Chapman's (G.B.) Co. Va. Light Arty. (Chapman's Battery), 1903 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Chapman's (W.H.) Co. Va. Light Arty. (Dixie Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Clutter's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Jackson's Flying Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Coffin's Co. Va. Heavy Arty. (Bethel Arty.) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1864-1865 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Coleman's Co. Va. Heavy Arty. (Neblett's Heavy Arty.), 1864 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Curtis' Co. Va. Arty. (Fredericksburg Artillery - 2nd) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Cutshaw's Co. Va. Light Artillery (Jackson Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Dance's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Powhatan Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Davidson's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Letcher Arty.) (part of Provisional Army) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Donald's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Rockbridge Artillery - 2nd), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Douthat's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Botetourt Artillery), 1867 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Ellet's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Crenshaw's Battery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1913 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Epes' Co. Va. Light Arty. (Johnson Arty.), 1911 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - French's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Giles Light Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Fry's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Orange Artillery), 1936 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Garber's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Staunton Artillery)(See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1913 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Graham's (Archibald) Co. Va. Light Arty. (Rockbridge Artillery - 1st), 1896-1906 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Graham's (Edward) Co. Va. Horse Arty. (Petersburg Artillery), 1865-1909 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Griffin's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Salem Light Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1899-1910 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Guerrant's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Goochland Light Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1904 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Hankins' Co. Va. Light Arty. (Surry Light Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Hardwicke's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Lee Battery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Huckstep's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Fluvanna Light Artillery -1st) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1861-1884 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Jackson's Co. Va. Horse Arty. (formerly Hale's Co.), 1905-1915 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Jeffress' Co. Va. Light Arty. (Nottoway Light Artillery), 1912 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Johnston's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Albemarle Artillery), 1899 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Jones' Co. Va. Heavy Arty. (Pamunkey Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1914 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Kirkpatrick's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Amherst Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1863-1911 (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Kyle's Co. Va. Heavy Arty., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Lamkin's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Nelson Light Artillery), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Leake's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Turner Arty.), 1904 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Lowry's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Centreville Rifles), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Lurty's Co. Va. Horse Arty., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 43)
      - McGregor's Battery (Stuart Horse Arty.), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Montgomery's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Morris Arty.) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1885 (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - Moore's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Huger Battery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 46)
      - Motley's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Pittsylvania Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 47)
      - Nelson's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Hanover Artillery), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 48)
      - Paris' Co. Va. Arty. (Stanton Hill Arty.), 1908-1921 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Parker's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Parker Battery), 1896-1930 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Pegram's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Branch Field Artillery), 1911 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Penick's Co. Va. Light Arty. (formerly Lewis' Co.), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Pollock's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Fredericksburg Artillery), 1884-1915 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Price's (Berryman) Co. Va. Light Arty. (Danville Artillery), 1912-1915 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Price's (Henry) Co. Va. Heavy Arty. (Price's Battery) (See Oversized - Box 1), 1884 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Rice's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Eighth Star Artillery) (New Market Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1911 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Richardson's Co. Va. Light Arty. (James City Artillery), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Rives' Co. Va. Light Arty. (Nelson Light Artillery), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Rodgers' Co. Va. Light Arty. (Loudoun Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1861-1914 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Shank's Co. Va. Horse Arty. (formerly Breathed's Co.) (formerly Pelham's Co.) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1900-1902 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Shoemaker's Co. Va. Horse Arty. (Beauregard Rifles) (See Also Oversized - Box 1), 1884-1913 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Smith's (J.D.) Co. Va. Light Arty. (Bedford Light Artillery), 1903-1937 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Tanner's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Courtney Artillery) (Henrico Artillery) (See Also Oversized - Box 1) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1863-1884 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Thompson's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Grimes' Battery) (Portsmouth Light Arty), 1884 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Thornton's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Caroline Artillery), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Wimbish's Co. Va. Light Arty. (Long Island Light Artillery), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 18)